Finding Aid for Mary Elizabeth Cooley papers, ca. 1920s-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mary Elizabeth Cooley papers ca. 1920s-1978
Cooley, Mary Elizabeth.
0.5 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
85169 Aa 2
Assistant to the director of the Hopwood Awards program at the University of Michigan; correspondence relating in part to her research into the life and career of American admiral and explorer, Charles Wilkes.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Dorothy L. Tyler (donor no. 5092 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Mary Elizabeth Cooley was an instructor in geology at Mt. Holyoke College. She later became assistant to the director of the Hopwood Awards program at the University of Michigan.
The collection consists of correspondence relating to her research into the life and career of American admiral and explorer, Charles Wilkes. There are also papers concerning her father, sociologist, Charles Horton Cooley. Some of her correspondents include William H. Hobbs, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, and Dorothy Tyler.
Subjects:
Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Avery Hopwood and Jule Hopwood Prizes.
Contributors:
Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1879-1962.; Tyler, Dorothy.
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - Letters to mother, ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 1)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1933 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936-1938 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1939 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1939 (Box 1)
  - January-March 1940 (Box 1)
  - April-June 1940 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966, 1970 (Box 1)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - 1976-1978 (Box 2)
- Other materials
  - Papers re. estate of Charles H. Cooley (Box 2)
  - Papers re. career of Charles H. Cooley (Box 2)
  - Papers re. Charles Wilkes (Box 2)
  - Articles of Dorothy Tyler (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea (Box 2)